Ibragim Zubailov

Senior Software Engineer with experience in: Node.js, Go, Database, Team & Tech Leadership

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Business-oriented, flexible, communicative, with an emphasis on results.

With load under 500k rps(input), and number of users (up to 1 million)

Worked with Enterprise and Startup companies, in teams from 3 to 20 people.

Project type experience: AdTech(OpenRTB), Gambling, Blockchain, GameDev, Storage

SKILLS

Programming: Go, TypeScript, Node.js, NestJS, Web3(Blockchain) Storage: Clickhouse, Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Aerospike Transport: Kafka, RabbitMQ, NATS, GRPC, GraphQL, Websockets

Others: GlusterFS, ElasticSearch, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Nginx, Prometheus, Grafana

WORK EXPERIENCE (6 YEARS)

MTS Group Moscow, Russia Jun 2022 — Jun 2023 · Remote (1 \mathbf{v} .)

Senior Go and Node.js Developer

- Identified a balance issue between storage systems and developed a service to optimize load handling.
- Eliminated a bottleneck in data retrieval from storage, increasing performance 10x.
- Facilitated team operations by creating tools for workflow simplification, which enhanced overall team productivity.

Loftv

Teamlead (8 BACKEND GO DEVELOPERS) May $2020 - \text{May } 2022 \cdot \text{Hybrid } (2y.)$

- Analyzed data to pinpoint key growth areas for advertising arbitrage (OpenRTB).
- Streamlined team processes: incorporated **KPIs**, a roadmap, an idea board, task decomposition.
- Devised a traffic quality forecasting system to optimize costs and filtering for SSP.
- Conceived and developed a system for assessment and filtration (Antifraud), ensuring quality for DSP.
- Boosted the annual profit from 0 to 1 million USD in two years, in high-load product with under 500k rps.

Techlead (4 BACKEND NODE.JS DEVELOPERS)

Oct 2019 — May 2020 · On-site (8m.)

- Overhauled an application to achieve stability, 3x performance, and A/B testing capability, which enabled performance enhancement from 15k to 150k RPS over two years.
- Implemented Agile, optimized hiring and staff adaptation processes.
- Contributed to architectural design and DevOps, enhancing data storage efficiency.

Senior Node.js Developer

Jul 2019 — Oct 2019 · On-site (4m.)

- Developed a high-load (70k rps) service for sending push notifications with extensive customization options.
- Created a microservice for authorization.

Belsona Investment Group

Moscow, Russia

Moscow, Russia

Node.js Developer

Jun 2017 — Jul 2019 · On-site (2y.)

- Engineered a bot for arbitrage between **blockchain smart contracts** and exchanges (**Binance/Bitfinex**).
- Created a risk assessment and predictive market trend model based on blockchain data.
- Implemented automated scripts to reduce routine tasks, particularly for ICO projects.
- Developed a service for calculating risks of ICO products.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information System Security

Sep $2013 - \text{May } 2017 \ (4y.)$